Guide to the Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004.
Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004
- Series VI. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2008
  - Project Proposal: Scalable Cities, Brown, Sheldon (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Scalable City—New Trailer
      - Scalable City: Shanghai Moca Documentation
      - Smoke and Mirrors-Overview Video
      - Excerpts
  - Project Proposal: THWONK: Where You Design the Rules of Online Communication!, Brucker-Cohen, Jonah (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples(includes videos of artworks PoliceState (2003), Alerting Infrastructure! (2003), Scrapyard Challenge Workshops (2003), SimpleTEXT (2003), as well as a slideshow of other projects)
      - Coin-Op Interactive Projects: Supplemental Work Samples(includes documentation of artworks Internetradio, Search Engine, site-traffic.net, Crank the Web, Phonetic Faces, Drawbots, Scroller, SimpleTEXT, Mouse Miles, Alerting Infrastructure, PoliceState, CineWindow, tele-tv, IPO Madness)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - PoliceState: Protect Serve Subvert
      - Alerreting Infrastructure! (2003)
      - SimpleTEXT: A Cell Phone Enabled Interactive Performance (2003)
      - Scrapyard Challenge Workshops (2003)
      - BumpList: An Email Community for the Determined (2003)
      - Umbrella_Net (2004)
      - Search Engine (2001)
      - Internet IPO Madness (2001)
      - Mouse Miles (2002)
  - Project Proposal: Total Internal Reflection, Campbell, Jim (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - DVD:
      - Documentation(includes documentation of artworks in the series Memory Works (includes Photo of my Mother, 1996; Portrait of my Father 1994-95; I Have Never Read the Bible, 1995; Typing Paper 1995; Cyclical Meter base:time 1996; Cyclical Counter base:time 1996); Experiments in Touching Color (1999); the Ambiguous Icons series (2007); Last Day in the Beginning of March (2003); Wave Map (2006); Peripheral Rhythm (2007))
  - Project Proposal: Autonomous Medical Industries [AMI], Cooper, Justine (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - DVD:
      - Havidol
    - Print and other materials:
      - Havidol promotional package(includes artist’s statement, comments from the Havidol website (5 pp), reproductions of print advertisements (2 pp) and promotional gear, postcard, exhibition announcement, sample pills, promotional mousepad, promotional t-shirt.)
  - Project Proposal: Capitalist Punishment, Daniel, Sharon (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - DVD:
      - Data DVD DVD #1(Quicktime screen capture of Public Secret website)
      - Data DVD Disc #2(Quicktime screen capture of Palabras website)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Public Secrets
      - Blood Sugar
      - Palabras
  - Project Proposal: Call Me Ishmael, Davis, Joe (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - CD-ROM:
      - CD-R Quicktime Movs(includes images, video documentation, and technical drawings of prototype air lasers, as well as image and video files made with the artist’s audiomicroscope)
  - Project Proposal: Walden, a game, Fullerton, Tracy (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - DVD:
      - Tracy Fullerton Sample Works(includes trailers for The Night Journey, 2007, and for proposed project Walden, a game)
    - DVD-Rom:
      - The Night Journey(playable version of 2007 PC game)
  - Project Proposal: Contaminating the Preserve: A Sedimentary Tour, Griffis, Ryan (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - DVD:
      - Griffis Sample Work 2007(includes demos of artworks Guanabacoa Trail Proposal (2006-7); Parking Public (2005-7); Tour of the Chicago Technology Park (2004); Postcard from Eutopia (2003))
      - Parking Public: A Tour into the Storage of Utopia(2007; accompanied by print project description and credits)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Griffis Supplemental Work(portfolio including description and documentation of artworks Ash Site Annex (2007); Lofoten Emergency Tourist Kit (2004); The Great Disassembly of 2008 Tour (2007); Invisible Trajectories (2007); Bioremediation Plot Network: a proposal for a monument (2005))
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Guanabacoa Trail Proposal
      - Parking Public
      - Tour of the Chicago Technology Park
      - Postcard from Eutopia
      - Ash Site Annex
      - Lofoten Emergency Tourist Kit
      - The Great Disassembly of 2008 Tour
      - Invisible Trajectories
  - Project Proposal: The Gifted Traveler, Harris, Jonathon (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Jonathan Harris Media Arts Fellowship(includes descriptions and documentation of artworks Yahoo! Time Capsule (2006), 10x10: 100 Words and Pictures that Define the Time (2004), Wordcount: Tracking the Way We Use Language (2004), and Phylotaxis (2005), and descriptions, documentation, and local copies of web artworks We Feel Fine: An Exploration of Human Emotion (2006), The Whale Hunt: A Storytelling Experiment (2007), and Universe: Revealing Our Modern Mythology (2007))[info CD with Sketchbooks and press packet, and slides not received]
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - We Feel Fine
      - The Whale Hunt: A Storytelling Experiment
      - Universe: Revealing Our Modern Mythology
      - 10x10: 100 Words and Pictures that Define the Time
      - Wordcount: Tracking the Way We Use Language
      - Wordcount: Tracking the Way We Use Language
      - Phylotaxis
  - Project Proposal: Street Spirit, Iverson, Hana (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Print Materials:
      - Susan Chevlowe, “Meetings of Past and Present: The Installations of Multimedia Artists Hana Iverson and Melissa Shiff,” NASHIM: A Journal of Jewish Women’s Studies and Gender Issues, 2007. B/W photocopy.
      - “Bridging the Analog/Digital Divide”, article in Temple University Faculty Herald, 17 no. 1(color print from web)
      - Review from Art in America(includes color image of installation View from the Balcony, 2007)
      - “World of Our Mothers,” review in The Village Voice(photocopy)
      - “Weaving a History,” article in The Philadelphia Inquirer(color photocopy)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - View from the Balcony
      - Cross/Walks: Weaving Fabric Row
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Philadelphia Inquirer article about Cross/Walks: Weaving Fabric Row
      - Bridging the Analog/Digital Divide: Presss description of educational work at Temple University
      - Neighborhood Narratives curriculum, published as part of Leonardo eJournal section on Locative Media
  - Project Proposal: Bronzeville SL, Jones, Philip (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - DVD-ROM:
      - Phillip Mallory Jones Renew Media Fellowship Samples(includes powerpoint slideshows of artworks In the Sweet Bye and Bye in Second Life (2007), Lissen Here! (2004), and digital images from several other projects(2001-2007))
  - Project Proposal: Timed Release: A Series of Performative Portraits, Kumao, Heidi (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - DVD:
      - Work Samples(includes documentation of projects Misbehaving (2002-2007, Timed Release (2006), Wired Wear (2005-2007), EmotionMachine (2000-2001), CNNplusplus (2006), Hidden Mechanisms (1999))
    - CD-ROM:
      - JPEG images
    - Print Materials:
      - Exhibition announcement for Heidi Kumao: Misbehaving: Media Machines Act Out
  - Project Proposal: Radiation Burn, Kurtz, Steve (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - DVD:
      - (Not Received) (includes demos of installations Immolation (2007), GenTerra (2001), The City Srapys Back (2007), Molecular Invasion (2003), Free Range Grain (2004))
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Molecular Invasion
  - Project Proposal: Grabeland – open source, Lamprecht, Franziska/Moderegger, Hajoe (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - DVD:
      - International Airport Montello (2007)
      - The Paradox of the 10 Acre Square (2005)
      - 1.1 Acre Flat Screen (2004)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - International Airport Montello full site
      - selected pages
      - selected pages
      - selected pages
      - The Paradox of the 10 Acre Square
      - 1.1 Acre Flat Screen
    - Print Materials:
      - color photocopies of articles, including b/w and color photographs of project International Airport Montello:
      - Tom Vanderbilt, “One-Way Ticket to Nowhere,” Modern Painters, November 2006, 52-54
      - Kris Vagner, “Gate Crashing,” Nevada Today, September 28, 2006
  - Project Proposal: Eye Contact Systems, Levin, Golan (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - DVD (2 copies):
      - Work Samples(includes samples of artworks Opto-Isolator(2007), Messa di Voce (2003-4), Manual Input Sessions (2004), Biotopes Tables (2004), Ursonography 2005), Scrapple (2005), Re:MARK (2002), Dialtones (2001))
    - CD-Rom:
      - Installation Diagrams and Supplemental Slides(Includes diagrams of proposed project, Work-In-Progress Photos, PDF of Visual Brochure, and application forms)
    - Print Materials:
      - Visual Brochure (spiral-bound portfolio with text descriptions and many full-color images of the artists’ works)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Opto-Isolator
      - Messa di Voce
      - Manual Input Sessions
      - Ursonography
      - Scrapple
      - Re:MARK
      - Dialtones
  - Project Proposal: They Rule, We Work, On, Josh (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - They Rule
      - Antiwargame
      - Inequality
      - Communiculture
      - Autodidactic
      - Texan Drawl
      - Texan Drawl
      - Election Quizzes
      - Election Quizzes
  - Project Proposal: Mapping Sanctuary, Polak, Jenny (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Jenny Polak New Media 07 Supplemental Materials(includes local versions of web projects Hard Place (2002) and Design for the Alien Within (2006), and slides of other projects)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Hard Place
      - Design for the Alien Within
      - ICE Raids Tracking Map (2007)
  - Project Proposal: 90˚ S, Polli, Andrea (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - DVD:
      - The Queensbridge Wind Power Project (2004)
    - Audio CD:
      - Atmospherics/Weather Works (2003)
      - N. (2007)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Andrea Polli(includes slides documenting various projects, 200-2006)
    - Print Materials:
      - color photocopies of selected reviews; includes photographs
  - Project Proposal: n.udge, Raaf, Sabrina (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Sabrina Raaf Renew Media 2008(includes videos of artworks Translator II: Grower (2004), Curtain Wall (2008), Icelandic Rift (2006), Lost (2003), Unstoppable Hum (2000), search.store.trash (2003). as well as digital versions of the artist’s CV and fellowship proposal and relevant published articles and reviews)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Translator II: Grower
      - Icelandic Rift
      - Lost
      - Unstoppable Hum
      - search.store.trash
  - Project Proposal: (Untitled), Reas, C.E.B. (Casey) (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - DVD-ROM:
      - Casey Reas 2008 New Media Media Arts Fellow (includes still images QuickTime videos of artworks TI (2004), Process 4-16 (2005-7), Process 8 (Image 1) (2006), Images for 18 Musicians (2004) and text file to accompany website {Software} Structures (2004))
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - TI
      - {Software} Structures
      - {Software} Structures
      - {Software} Structures
      - Process 4-16
      - Process 8 (Image 1)
      - Images for 18 Musicians
  - Project Proposal: The Sculptural User Installation: Social Sculpture as Tree-ed Binary Large Object, Rees, Michael (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - DVD-ROM:
      - Michael Rees 2008(includes slideshow of artist’s works, applications Sculptural User Interface and m_machine)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - m_machine
  - Project Proposal: Intertwine, Rinaldo, Ken (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - DVD:
      - Ken Rinaldo: Exploring the confluence and coevolution of organic and technological cultures(includes videos of artworks The Autotelematic Spider Bots (2006), Augmented Fish Reality (2004), Spider Haus (2001), Autopoesis (2000), Standby Deliver (2000), Flickering Signifiers (2000), Mediated Encounters (1998), Delicate Balance (1993), and clip about the artist from TV program The Know Zone (1995)) (2 copies)
    - CD-ROM:
      - 10 jpgs of Intertwine(visualizations of proposed project)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - The Farm Fountain
    - Print materials:
      - glossy prints of proposed project visualizations(duplicates jpgs on CD-ROM)
      - Press portfolio with color copies/originals of related articles and reviews
  - Project Proposal: CUBE, Schatz, Lincoln (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - DVD:
      - Recent Work 2007(Video documentation of Generative Portraits, 2005-2007)
      - Lincoln Schatz: Cube 2007(includes CUBE portraits of Jeff Dauber, Chris Houston, Beau Takahara, Craig Newmark, Joe Shanahan, Betsey and Dale Pinkert, Jorge Simes, Annie Sprinkle and Beth Stephens, Ken Goldberg and Tiffany Shlain, and Daniel Herskovic)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Lincoln Schatz: Supplemental JPGs and Press Materials(includes slides of recent work and pdfs of press materials)
  - Project Proposal: Endangered Senses, Schusterman, Gemma (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - DVD-ROM:
      - Gemma Shusterman Sample Work(includes videos of projects Super Elephant, superCloaca, i am here for you (2005), Faunacise: Exercise for the Animal Behind the Desk (2005), tilt (2007), 3x3 (2004))
    - CD-ROM:
      - Gemma Shusterman JPG Sildes(still images of selected artworks)
    - Print Materials:
      - Press packet(color copies of relevant articles and reviews, in English, Spanish, and Italian)
  - Project Proposal: Superfund365, Singer, Brooke (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - DVD-ROM:
      - Singer Sample Works 1 Backup(includes offline versions of websites Superfund 365, AIR: Area’s Immediate Reading, and The U.S. Oil Fix)
      - Singer Sample Works 2 Backup(videos of interviews related to proposed project)
      - Singer Supplemental(includes video 800 Steps Apart)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Superfund365
      - Superfund365
      - Superfund365
      - AIR: Area’s Immediate Reading
      - AIR: Area’s Immediate Reading
      - AIR: Area’s Immediate Reading
      - The U.S. Oil Fix
      - 800 Steps Apart
  - Project Proposal: Love Tells Me I Am Everything, Snibbe, Scott Sona (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - DVD:
      - Interactive Media Art by Scott Snibbe(includes demos of projects Boundary Functions (1998), Visceral Cinema: Chien (2004), Deep Walls (2002), Cause and Effect (2004), Shadow and Substance (in progress at time of submission), Falling Girl (in progress at time of submission))
    - Slides
      - (Not Received)
  - Project Proposal: Realm of the Puddle, Spelletich, Kal (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - DVD-ROM:
      - Kal Spelletich Supplemental Materials(includes still images of artworks Fireshower, Flightsimulator, Keep Your Feet in the Air/Head On the Ground, Leopard Purr Hugging Machine, Lighter Than Air Installation, Master Mind Machine, Monkey On Your Back, Telerobotic BEER ME MACHINE, The Kiss, Vino Viper)
    - DVD:
      (includes documentation of works Master Mind Machine, Hugger Mugger, Monkey On Your Back, Flight Simulator, Feet in the Air, Vino Viper, Fireshower, Fiddler, BEER ME, documentation of Kal Spelletich Fringe Exhibitions, and other projects)
      - Supplemental Video Work for Kal Spelletich(includes documentation of robotic works Beer Me and Fiddler, and video footage of two gallery shows)
  - Project Proposal: Raw Data: Personal Visceral Devices, Utterback, Camille (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - DVD:
      - Sample Works Camille Utterback(includes documentation of installations Text Rain (1999), see/saw (2001), Liquid Time (series, 2001-2002), Potent Objects (2003 series, featured works: Shaken and Balance), Untitled 5 (2004), and Abundance (2007))
    - Slides
      - (Not Received)
  - Project Proposal: Latent Figure Protocol, Vanouse, Paul (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - DVD:
      - Relative Velocity Inscription Device (2002)
      - Latent Figure Protocol (in progress)
      - Active Stimulation Feedback Platform (2005)
      - Paradise Reconfigured (2000)
      - Terminal Time (2000)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Relative Velocity Inscription Device
      - Latent Figure Protocol
      - Active Stimulation Feedback Platform
      - Paradise Reconfigured
      - Terminal Time
  - Project Proposal: Book From the Ground, Xu, Bing (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Xu Bing Sample Works(includes documentation and samples from artworks Book From the Sky (1991), An Introduction to Squareword Calligraphy (1996), Your Surname Please (1998), Excuse me sir, can you tell me how to get to the Asia Society? (2001), Dynamic Desktop (2006), Book from the Ground (in progress))
      - Xu Bing Supplemental Works(includes pdf files of two articles, David Ng, “Messaging is the Medium,” ArtNews Summer 2007, 186-187; Kevin Kwong, “Character Building,” The South China Morning Post, Nov. 12, 2006, p. 8)